Register of the Karl August Wittfogel papers, 1728-1992
Hoover Institution Archives
Karl August Wittfogel papers,
1728-1992
66033
Wittfogel, Karl August, 1896-1988
408 manuscript boxes, 11 card file boxes, 2 oversize boxes, 6 album boxes, 61 envelopes, 1 oversize folder, 15 microfilm reels, 1 videotape cassette, 2 phonorecords, 19 slides (183 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Speeches and writings, memoirs, correspondence, notes, studies, reports, printed matter, and audiovisual materials, relating to the history of China from ancient times to the twentieth century; the development of Chinese studies in the West; the concept of an Asiatic mode of production; and the history of German, Russian, Chinese and international communist movements. Includes some papers of Esther Schiff Goldfrank and G. L. Ulmen.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1966.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in Socrates is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Communism.; Communism--Germany.; Communism--China.; Asiatic mode of production.; China--Study and teaching.; Germany.; Soviet Union.; Russia (Federation); Chin.a; United States.; Civilization, Oriental.; Communism--Soviet Union.; Slides (Photography); Phonorecords.; Video tapes.; Goldfrank, Esther Schiff.; Ulmen, G. L.
Biography
1896, Sept. 6 Born, Woltersdorf, Germany
1912 Joined the German youth movement Wandervogel
1917 Drafted, German Army Signal Corps
1918 Joined the Unabhangige Sozialdemokratische Partei
1920-1921 Teacher, Volkshochschule Schloss Tinz, Tinz, Germany
1920 Joined the Kommunistische Partei Deutschlands
1921 Married Rose Schlesinger
Author, Rote Soldaten: Politische Tragodie in 5 Akten
1922 Author,
Der Mann, der eine Idee hat
Die Mutter, Der Fluchtling
Vom Urkommunismus bis zur proletarischen Revolution
Die Wissenschaft der burgerlichen Gesellschaft: Eine marxistische Untersuchung
1923 Author, Wer ist der Dummste?
1924 Author,
Geschichte der burgerlichen Gesellschaft: Von ihren
Anfangen bis zur Schwelle der grossen Revolution
Der Wolkenkratzer: Amerikanischer Sketch
1924-1925 Author, Die spannenden Abenteuer des 12 jahrigen Freiheitshelden Antonio Mascaro im Bauernaufstand zu Mallorka
1925 Cultural editor, Die Rote Fahne
1925-1933 Research associate, Institut fur Sozialforschung, Universitat Frankfurt, Germany
1926 Author, Das erwachende China: Ein Abriss der Geschichte der gegenwartigen Probleme Chinas
1928 Ph.D. in economics, Universitat Frankfurt
1931 Author, Wirtschaft und Gesellschaft Chinas: Versuch der wissenschaftlichen Analyse einer grossen asiatischen Agrargesellschaft
1933 Married Olga Joffe
Arrested; spent nine months in prison and in three
concentration camps
1934 Left Germany for England and then the United States
1934-1939 Research associate, International Institute of Social Research, associated with and located on the campus ofColumbia University, New York City (formerly the Institutfur Sozialforschung)
1935-1937 Researcher in China
1936 Author (under the pseudonym Klaus Hinrichs), Staatliches Konzentrationslager VII
1939 Joined the Wider Quaker Fellowship
Broke with the Communist movement after the Nazi-Soviet Pact
1939-1968 Founder and director, Chinese History Project, Columbia University, New York City (co-sponsored by the Institute of Pacific Relations and the International Institute of Social Research, and after 1947, by the University of Washington and Columbia University)
1940 Married Esther S. Goldfrank
1941 Naturalized American citizen
1943-1944 Lecturer in Chinese, Columbia University, New York City
1944-1945 Associate Professor in International Studies, Columbia University, New York City
1945-1946 Associate Professor in the University Seminars, Columbia University, New York City
1947-1949 Acting professor of Chinese History, University of Washington, Seattle
1949 Author (with Feng Chia-sheng), History of Chinese Society: Liao (907-1125)
1949 Joined the American Committee for Cultural Freedom
1949-1966 Professor of Chinese History, University of Washington, Seattle
1950 Subpoenaed to appear before the House Committee on Un-American Activities in executive session
1951 Subpoenaed to appear before the Internal Security Subcommittee of the Senate Judiciary Committee in open session
1957 Author, Oriental Despotism: A Comparative Study of Total Power
1960 Author, From Marx to Mao: A Viewer's Guide
1966-1988 Distinguished Professor Emeritus, University of Washington, Seattle
1977 Author, Beitrage zur marxistischen Asthetik
1988, May 25 Died, New York City
Series Description
- BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, 1831-1987. (Boxes 1-4)
  Articles, clippings, legal documents, memoirs, memoranda and notes arranged by physical form
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1907-1988. (Boxes 5-56)
  Arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent
- NOTES, n.d. (Boxes 57-63)
  Reading notes and excerpts arranged alphabetically by topic
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1913-1990. (Boxes 64-120)
  Articles, autobiographical notes, drafts of books, essays, index cards, memoirs, notes, speeches, and related research material and correspondence, arranged chronologically by title
- UNFINISHED WRITING PROJECTS, 1956-1984. (Boxes 121-151)
  Drafts of projected books, arranged alphabetically by title
- COURSE MATERIAL, 1943-1970. (Boxes 152-154)
  Notes and correspondence arranged alphabetically by university
- SUBJECT FILE, 1797-1987. (Boxes 155-242)
  Pamphlets, clippings, articles, reports, and conference papers arranged alphabetically by topic
- CHINESE HISTORY PROJECT, 1936-1977. (Boxes 243-286)
  Prepared data sheets, correspondence, financial records, memoranda, notes, and published and unpublished writings arranged by physical form
- CHINESE LANGUAGE MATERIALS, n.d. (Boxes 287-290)
  (unsorted)
- ESTHER SCHIFF GOLDFRANK PAPERS, 1917-1987. (Boxes 291-293)
  Published and unpublished writings, notes, correspondence, articles, and clippings arranged by physical form
- GARY L. ULMEN PAPERS, 1964-1986. (Boxes 294-295)
  Published and unpublished writings and correspondence arranged by physical form
- INDEX CARD FILE, n.d. (Boxes 296-306)
  Address and bibliographic, biographic, and reference note files arranged alphabetically by file
- PHONOTAPE REELS, n.d. (Boxes 307-309)
  Phonotape reels of reminiscences by Wittfogel. In English
  - Tape 1, Memories, undated; A transcription is available. In English (307)
    Use copy reference number: 66033_a_0001434
- MICROFILM REELS, 1832-1938.
  Microfilm copies of published articles and reference materials arranged alphabetically by subject
- PHONORECORDS n.d. (Record cabinet)
  Phonorecords of Native American and Brazilian Indian music arranged alphabetically by title
- VIDEOTAPE CASSETTE, 1982. (Tape cabinet)
  Recording of lecture by Wittfogel on Oriental Despotism given in Germany
- OVERSIZE MATERIALS, 1919-1954. (Map case)
  Placards announcing speeches, research materials for the Chinese History Project, and lithographs
- PHOTOGRAPHS., 61 envelopes, 6 album boxes, 1 slide box. (66033 - 10.A-V, 57.05, slide cabinet)
Container List
- BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, 1831-1987
  - Address books and calling cards (Box 1., Folder 1-3)
  - Articles, clippings and papers about or mentioning KAW, his life and his work, particularly Oriental Despotism
    - Undated (Folder 4)
    - 1931 (Folder 5)
    - 1953-1959 (Folder 6)
    - 1960-1967 (Folder 7)
    - 1970-1979 (Folder 8)
    - 1981-1987 (Folder 9)
    - 1981-1987 (Box 2., Folder 1)
  - Autobiographical notes relating to KAW's intellectual development (Folder 2)
  - Awards and honors
    - General (Folder 3)
    - A. Cressy Morrison Award (Folder 4)
    - Festschrift (Folder 5)
  - Bibliographies
    - General (Folder 6)
    - China (Folder 7)
    - Mao Tse-tung (Folder 8)
  - Biographical sketches (Folder 9)
  - Daily reminder calendars
    - 1938-1947 (Folder 10)
    - 1950-1965 (Folder 11)
    - 1966-1972 (Box 3., Folder 1)
    - 1973-1980 (Folder 2)
    - 1981-1985 (Folder 3)
  - Diary, 1908 (Folder 4)
  - Honoraria and guest lecture appearances (Folder 5)
  - Legal documents
    - General (Folder 6)
    - Birth certificate (Folder 7)
    - Education (Folder 8)
    - Immigration and naturalization (United States) (Folder 9)
    - Imprisonment (1933)
      - General (Folder 10)
      - Restitution (1957) (Folder 11)
    - Last will and testament (Folder 12)
    - Marriage licenses and divorce agreements
      - Rose Schlesinger (1921, 1930) (Folder 13)
      - Olga Joffe (1932, 1939) (Folder 14)
      - Esther S. Goldfrank (1940) (Folder 15)
    - Visas and passports
      - Germany (Folder 16)
      - Great Britain (Folder 17)
      - United States (Folder 18)
  - Memberships (Folder 19)
  - Memoirs by Olga Joffe (KAW's second wife), ca. 1941 (Box 4., Folder 1)
  - Memoranda relating to KAW's work (Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous. Includes 2 Reichsbanknote (Folder 3)
  - Notes (Folder 4)
  - Oral history. Memoranda and correspondence (Folder 5)
  - Subject file
    - Family members
      - General (Folder 6)
      - Wittfogel, Albert (Folder 7)
      - Wittfogel, Johann Christoph (Folder 8)
      - Wittfogel, Johann Joachim Heinrich. Autobiography, 1862. Holograph (Folder 9)
      - Wittfogel, Johanne Magdalene Auguste (Schulze) (Folder 10)
      - Wittfogel, Heinz (Folder 11)
    - Retirement (Folder 12)
    - Student years (Folder 13)
    - Travel
      - Australia, 1970 (Folder 14)
      - Japan, 1957 (Folder 15)
      - Europe, 1979 (Folder 16)
      - Taiwan, 1957-1958 (Folder 17)
      - Thailand, ca. 1970 (Folder 18)
      - United States, 1973 (Folder 19)
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1907-1988.
  Includes some correspondence of Gary L. Ulmen. See also NOTES, China
  - General
    - Book and journal orders (Box 5., Folder 1)
    - Invitations (declined)
      - Speaking engagements (Folder 2)
      - Written contributions (Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous (Folder 4)
    - Requests
      - Biographical information (Folder 5)
      - Reprints (Folder 6)
      - Reproduction permissions (Folder 7)
      - Research information (Box 6., Folder 1)
  - Unidentified
    - Undated (Folder 2)
    - 1903 (Folder 3)
    - 1913 (Folder 4-5)
    - 1914 (Folder 6)
    - 1914-1915 (Folder 7)
    - 1915 (Folder 8)
    - 1918-1919 (Folder 9)
    - 1922 (Folder 10)
    - 1929 (Folder 11)
    - 1930s (Folder 12-15)
    - 1940s (Folder 16)
    - 1940s-1950s (Folder 17)
    - 1950s (Folder 18-21)
    - 1950s-1980s (Folder 22)
    - 1960s (Folder 23)
    - 1970s (Folder 24)
    - 1980s (Folder 25)
  - Ackerman, Adolph J., 1957-1972 (Box 7., Folder 1)
  - Ackerman, Phyllis, 1944-1946 (Folder 2)
  - Adair, John, 1959 (Folder 3)
  - Adams, Inez, 1949-1950 (Folder 4)
  - Adelphi Edizioni, 1963 (Folder 5)
  - Aerospace Industry Purchasing Seminar, 1962 (Folder 6)
  - Ahlenstiel, Heinz, 1946-1967. Includes letter from Tina Wommelsdorf (Folder 7)
  - Ahlenstiel, Rolf, 1959-1965 (Folder 8)
  - Aid Refugee Chinese Intellectuals, 1956 (Folder 9)
  - Aikman, David, 1970-1971 (Folder 10)
  - Aktion, 1952 (Folder 11)
  - Albrecht, William A., 1956 (Folder 12)
  - Albright, W. F., 1948-1950 (Folder 13)
  - Aleksandr Solzhenitsyn Society for Freedom and Justice (Edward J. Rozek), 1975-1976 (Folder 14)
  - Alexander, Robert J., 1967 (Folder 15)
  - Alfken, Hans, 1947-1948 (Folder 16)
  - All-American Conference to Combat Communism (Karl Baarslag), 1957-1958 (Folder 17)
  - Allen, Edwin Brown, 1949-1950 (Folder 18)
  - Allen, Raymond B. and Dorothy, 1949-1962. See also Kirkpatrick, Evron M. (Folder 19)
  - Allen, Richard V., 1966-1967 (Folder 20)
  - Allers, Ulrich S., 1962 (Folder 21)
  - Alternative (R. Emmett Tyrell, Jr.), 1973 (Folder 22)
  - Altschuler, Milton, 1958 (Folder 23)
  - Ambroz, Oton, 1972 (Folder 24)
  - Amerasia, 1937 (Folder 25)
  - American Anthropological Association, 1958-1977. Includes correspondence with William P. Mitchell and Barbara J. Price (Folder 26)
  - American Anthropologist (Raymond D. Fogelson, Councill Taylor), 1957-1966 (Folder 27)
  - American-Asian Educational Exchange
    - 1957-1960 (Folder 28)
    - 1961-1973 (Folder 29)
  - American Association of University Professors, 1979 (Folder 30)
  - American Association of University Women, 1958 (Folder 31)
  - American Bar Association, 1966 (Folder 32)
  - American Bureau for Medical Aid to China, 1974 (Folder 33)
  - American China Policy Association, 1950 (Folder 34)
  - American Committee for Cultural Freedom (Sol Stein), 1953-1955 (Folder 35)
  - American Council of Learned Societies (Mortimer Graves, Waldo G. Leland, Nancy Lee Swann), 1937-1948 (Folder 36)
  - American Enterprise Institute for Public Policy Research (William J. Baroody), 1964-1973 (Folder 37)
  - American Federation of Labor and Congress of Industrial Organizations (Jay Lovestone), 1956-1975 (Box 8., Folder 1)
  - American Friends Fellowship Council, 1939-1941 (Folder 2)
  - American Geographical Society, 1933-1939 (Folder 3)
  - American Historical Association (Walter C. Hucul), 1957 (Folder 4)
  - American Historical Review, 1955-1957 (Folder 5)
  - American Museum of Natural History (N. C. Nelson), 1945 (Folder 6)
  - American Philosophical Society (William E. Lingelbach). Includes correspondence with George E. Taylor and Raymond Dennett
    - 1942-1945 (Folder 7)
    - 1947-1950 (Folder 8)
    - 1967-1982 (Folder 9)
  - American Political Science Association, 1953-1971 (Folder 10)
  - American Political Science Review, 1958-1974 (Folder 11)
  - American Sociological Review, 1958-1967 (Folder 12)
  - American Sociological Society, 1958 (Folder 13)
  - American University (Yoon Chong-kun), 1967 (Folder 14)
  - Americans for Democratic Action (James Loeb, Jr.), 1951 (Folder 15)
  - Ampersand Ltd., 1965 (Folder 16)
  - Anderson, Edgar, 1955-1962 (Folder 17)
  - Andrzejewski, S., 1949-1952 (Folder 18)
  - Annales, 1966 (Folder 19)
  - Annals of the American Academy of Political and Social Science, 1953-1965 (Folder 20)
  - Anshen, Ruth Nanda, 1946 (Folder 21)
  - Anti-Defamation League (Oscar Cohen), 1955-1963 (Folder 22)
  - Antioch College, 1969 (Folder 23)
  - Anzengruber, Erika, 1946-1947 (Folder 24)
  - Arbeitsgemeinschaft Sozialpadagogik und Gesellschaftsbildung, 1979-1981 (Folder 25)
  - Armillas, Pedro, 1961 (Folder 26)
  - Arndt, Heinz W., 1970-1971 (Folder 27)
  - Asia Foundation (Lyman Hoover, David Steinberg), 1956-1958 (Folder 28)
  - Asthetik und Kommunikation, 1971 (Folder 29)
  - Athene Press, 1960 (Folder 30)
  - Atlantik-Brucke (Walter Stahl), 1958-1979 (Folder 31)
  - Atterbury, M. Daisy, 1950-1972 (Folder 32)
  - Australian Association for Cultural Freedom (H. Richard Krygier), 1956-1961 (Folder 33)
  - Australian National University (A. C. Basham, John G. Crawford, Rafe de Crespigny, Dirk van de Kaa, Eugene Kamenka, Hazel Richter, R. N. Robertson, Otto van der Sprenkel, Ling Wang, Jerzy Zubrzycki), 1969-1974 (Box 9., Folder 1)
  - Australian National University Press, 1971-1973 (Folder 2)
  - Avineri, Shlomo, 1971 (Folder 3)
  - Bach-Neuert, Herta, 1948-1980 (Folder 4)
  - Bacon, Maxine, 1966 (Folder 5)
  - Bailey, Anne M., 1977 (Folder 6)
  - Bailey, H. W., 1949 (Folder 7)
  - Baker, O. E., 1928 (Folder 8)
  - Balazs, Etienne (Stefan), 1945-1958 (Folder 9)
  - Bales, James D., 1957-1985 (Folder 10)
  - Bandyopadhyaya, Kalyani, 1971 (Folder 11)
  - Barbaria, Frank A., 1984 (Folder 12)
  - Barnard College, 1947-1964 (Folder 13)
  - Barnett, A. Doak, 1963-1967 (Folder 14)
  - Barnett, Robert W., 1984 (Folder 15)
  - Baron, Salo W., 1950 (Folder 16)
  - Baron, Samuel H., 1956-1974 (Folder 17)
  - Barral Editores, 1971 (Folder 18)
  - Bartosz, Andreas, 1982 (Folder 19)
  - Basadre, Jorge, 1958 (Folder 20)
  - Basil, John D., 1966-1972 (Folder 21)
  - Bates, Mrs. M. S., 1945 (Folder 22)
  - Bauernverband Berlin, 1967 (Folder 23)
  - Beaglehole, Ernest, 1940 (Folder 24)
  - Beard, Marles, 1947 (Folder 25)
  - Bearman, Sidney, 1966-1967 (Folder 26)
  - Beckmann, George M., 1969-1970 (Folder 27)
  - Beezley, P. C., 1960-1963 (Folder 28)
  - Bell, Aldon D., 1963 (Folder 29)
  - Bell, Daniel, 1960 (Folder 30)
  - Beloff, Max, 1959 (Folder 31)
  - Bengesser, Klaus, 1984-1986 (Folder 32)
  - Bennett, Josiah W., 1944-1945 (Folder 33)
  - Benson, George S., 1958 (Folder 34)
  - Bergman, Peter, 1948 (Folder 35)
  - Berry, Thomas, 1958-1964 (Folder 36)
  - Bertelsmann Universitatsverlag, 1971-1972 (Folder 37)
  - Bestor, Arthur, 1966 (Folder 38)
  - Bevan-Dunner, Ruth A., 1967-1982 (Folder 39)
  - Beyene, Mezgebe, 1974 (Box 10., Folder 1)
  - Beyer, Rolf and Jutta
    - Undated (Folder 2)
    - 1973-1976 (Folder 3)
    - 1977-1983 (Folder 4)
  - Bharati, Agehananda, 1961 (Folder 5)
  - Bierhoff, Alan F., n.d. (Folder 6)
  - Biester, Edward G., Jr., 1969 (Folder 7)
  - Biggerstaff, Knight, 1935-1947 (Folder 8)
  - Bilke, Jorg Bernhard, 1976 (Folder 9)
  - Bingham, Woodbridge, 1947 (Folder 10)
  - Bischoff, Friedrich, 1971-1975 (Folder 11)
  - Bishop, Carl Whiting, 1935-1941 (Folder 12)
  - Bishop, Charles, 1969 (Folder 13)
  - Blasch, Frieda, 1961 (Folder 14)
  - Blass, J. Lewis, 1946-1947 (Folder 15)
  - Bleiber, Fritz, 1957 (Folder 16)
  - Boba, Imre, 1962 (Folder 17)
  - Bochenski, J. M., 1956-1965. Includes correspondence with Tom Blakeley (Studies in Soviet Thought) (Folder 18)
  - Bodde, Derk, 1940-1950 (Folder 19)
  - Boecklen, Eileen J., 1957-1958 (Folder 20)
  - Bonn, Gisela, 1968 (Folder 21)
  - Bonne, Alfred, 1955 (Folder 22)
  - Boodberg, Peter A., 1949 (Folder 23)
  - Books for Libraries, 1972 (Folder 24)
  - Boorman, Howard L., 1955-1964 (Folder 25)
  - Borchardt, Elisabeth, 1947-1956 (Folder 26)
  - Borchers, Sofie, 1951 (Folder 27)
  - Borinski, Fritz, 1980-1981 (Folder 28)
  - Borochowicz, Elly, 1956-1967 (Folder 29)
  - Borton, Hugh, 1948 (Folder 30)
  - Bosch-Gimpera, Pedro, 1960 (Folder 31)
  - Botcher, W., 1915 (Folder 32)
  - Bottcher, Elke, 1969 (Folder 33)
  - Bradbury, William C., 1955 (Box 11., Folder 1)
  - Brake, Klaus, 1978-1982 (Folder 2)
  - Brand, Professor, 1962 (Folder 3)
  - Brandstraller, Professor, n.d. (Folder 4)
  - Brandt, Gerhard, 1979-1983 (Folder 5)
  - Brandt, Karl, 1962-1963 (Folder 6)
  - Branton, Rene and Paul, 1968-1980 (Folder 7)
  - Brendel, Xenia and Robert
    - Undated (Folder 8)
    - 1946-1949 (Folder 9)
    - 1950-1959 (Folder 10)
    - 1960-1969 (Folder 11)
    - 1970-1980 (Folder 12)
  - Brenner, Hildegard, 1971-1972 (Folder 13)
  - British Broadcasting Corporation, 1965 (Folder 14)
  - Britton, Roswell S., 1944 (Folder 15)
  - Broek, Jan, 1965 (Folder 16)
  - Bronstein, Leo, 1944 (Folder 17)
  - Broward Community College (Richard H. Furlow), 1978-1979 (Folder 18)
  - Brown, W. Norman, 1948 (Folder 19)
  - Brownfeld, Allan C., 1974 (Folder 20)
  - Bruce, Donald C., 1961 (Folder 21)
  - Bryan, Joseph, III, 1949 (Folder 22)
  - Brynes, Asher, 1947-1963 (Folder 23)
  - Brzezinski, Zbigniew, 1961-1963 (Folder 24)
  - Buber-Neumann, Margarete, 1962-1980 (Folder 25)
  - Buchhandlung Johannes Konig, 1955 (Folder 26)
  - Buck, John Lossing, 1935-1967 (Folder 27)
  - Bucknell Review, 1969 (Folder 28)
  - Budzinski, C. D., 1947-1949 (Folder 29)
  - Bull, Ludlow, 1948 (Folder 30)
  - Bulletin (Australian Consolidated Press Ltd.), 1966-1967 (Folder 31)
  - Bundeszentrale fur Heimatdienst, 1948-1959 (Folder 32)
  - Bundeszentrale fur Politische Bildung, 1967-1969 (Folder 33)
  - Bunker, Gerald Edward, 1967 (Folder 34)
  - Burks, Ardath W., 1956 (Folder 35)
  - Burnham, James, 1951-1956 (Folder 36)
  - Burton, Robert A., 1957-1958 (Folder 37)
  - Buschle, Albert, 1956-1960 (Folder 38)
  - Busse, Kurt H., 1964-1967 (Folder 39)
  - C. L. Hirschfeld Verlag, 1933 (Box 12., Folder 1)
  - Caddy, Douglas, 1960 (Folder 2)
  - Cahnman, Werner J., 1957-1958 (Folder 3)
  - Calliopean Society, 1961 (Folder 4)
  - Caltofen, Rodolfo, 1979 (Folder 5)
  - Candlin, A. H. S., 1968 (Folder 6)
  - Caponera, Dante A., 1965 (Folder 7)
  - Carnegie Corporation, 1958 (Folder 9)
  - Carrasco, Pedro, 1962-1981 (Folder 10)
  - Carter, Dagny, 1948 (Folder 11)
  - Carter, Edward C., 1934-1946 (Folder 12)
  - Carter, George F., 1947-1951 (Folder 13)
  - Casa Editrice Valentino Bompiani, 1965 (Folder 14)
  - Caskel, Werner, 1951 (Folder 15)
  - Cassinelli, Jose L., 1955 (Folder 16)
  - Cecil, Richard P., 1963-1968 (Folder 17)
  - Center for Advanced Studies in International Business, 1970 (Folder 18)
  - Center for Strategic Studies (David M. Abshire, Richard V. Allen), 1962-1963 (Folder 19)
  - Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions, 1970 (Folder 20)
  - Centro de Investigaciones Antropologicas de Mexico (Carmen Cook de Leonard), 1976 (Folder 21)
  - Centro Studi e Ricerche su Problemi Economico-Sociali (Renato Mieli), 1967-1969 (Folder 22)
  - Centro Studi Terzo Mondo (Umberto Melotti), 1972-1975 (Folder 23)
  - Chamberlain, John R., 1966 (Folder 24)
  - Chamberlain, Joseph P., 1947 (Folder 25)
  - Chambers, Whittaker, 1952 (Folder 26)
  - Chang, C. M., 1946-1947 (Folder 27)
  - Chang, Chung-li, 1954-1957 (Folder 28)
  - Chang, Chung-yuan, 1964 (Folder 29)
  - Chang, Kuo-tao, 1957-1959 (Folder 30)
  - Chao, Chen-sung, 1959-1972 (Folder 31)
  - Chappell, John, Jr., 1964-1966 (Folder 32)
  - Charles E. Tuttle Company, 1957-1958 (Folder 33)
  - Chavez-Ballon, Manuel, 1955 (Folder 34)
  - Chen, Chia-chih, 1943-1947 (Folder 35)
  - Chen, Shou-chiang, 1937 (Folder 36)
  - Cheng, Tao, 1963 (Folder 37)
  - Cheng, Tien-fong, 1957 (Folder 38)
  - Chiang, Kai-shek, n.d. (Folder 39)
  - Chiba, Masaji, 1958 (Folder 40)
  - Chih, Y. J., 1967 (Folder 41)
  - China Books and Periodicals, 1966 (Folder 42)
  - China Club of Seattle, 1959 (Folder 43)
  - China Institute in America, 1961-1964 (Folder 44)
  - China Mainland Press. See United States. Department of Commerce
  - China News Analysis, 1962-1983 (Folder 45)
  - China News Summary, 1966-1974 (Folder 46)
  - China Quarterly, 1959-1973 (Folder 47)
  - Chinese News Service, 1959-1962 (Box 13., Folder 1)
  - Chinese Students Club of Columbia University, 1960-1961 (Folder 2)
  - Chiu, Alfred K., 1947 (Folder 3)
  - Chiva, I., 1963-1964 (Folder 4)
  - Chou, Rita Jing-Ann, 1978 (Folder 5)
  - Chow, Raymond, 1958 (Folder 6)
  - Chu, Hsin-min, 1958 (Folder 7)
  - Chu, Tung-tsu, 1944-1962. See also Columbia University (Folder 8)
  - Chung, C. H., 1958 (Folder 9)
  - Chung, Tien-fung, 1956 (Folder 10)
  - Ciliga, Ante, 1966-1967 (Folder 11)
  - Citizens Committee for a Free Cuba, 1963-1967 (Folder 12)
  - City University of New York, 1979 (Folder 13)
  - Claessen, Henri J. M., 1973-1976 (Folder 14)
  - Clapp, Gordon R., 1947-1951 (Folder 15)
  - Clark, Hilma D., 1970-1972 (Folder 16)
  - Cleaves, Francis W., 1947-1948 (Folder 17)
  - Clubb, O. Edmund, 1936-1950 (Folder 18)
  - Cohen, Arthur A., 1965 (Folder 19)
  - Cohen, Elliot E., 1951-1957 (Folder 20)
  - Cohn, Michael, 1974-1981 (Folder 21)
  - Cole, Charles W., 1947-1948 (Folder 22)
  - Colebrook, Joan, 1972-1978 (Folder 23)
  - Collier Books (Richard P. Cecil, Howard Sandum), 1961-1965 (Folder 24)
  - Collier's Encyclopedia, 1959-1964 (Folder 25)
  - Columbia University (Ainslie T. Embree, John A. Krout, Andrew L. March, Stephen A. McCarthy, Peter Robert Roux)
    - 1942-1959 (Folder 26)